Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971; 585 (Box 1-7)
  - A hand-painted portrait of a young man in a suit and tarbouche. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid573; 1006; Studio Photo Diana, Bond Point, Daher (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Cairo, Egypt; Boys; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Furnishings
  - A group walking down on a street. 13.4 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid574; 1007; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Boys; Women; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - Men in suits with body builders/wrestlers. 8.8 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid575; 1008; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Sports; Men; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Boys; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A woman swimming. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid576; 1009; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Loutraki, Greece; Seas; Egypt; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Women; Individual Portraits
  - A negative image of two women with umbrellas standing on the beach in front of a hotel (ΠΗΓΗ ΚΑΡΑΝΤΑΝΗ). 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid577; 1010; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Loutraki, Greece; Architecture; Buildings; Hotels; Greek Writing; Negative Images; Photographic Prints; Umbrellas/Parasols; Beaches; Women; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Outdoors
  - Three men walking on a street. 12.9 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid578; 1011; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A mixed group with a gazelle. 8.8 x 11.1 cm, 17 October 1932; cuid579; 1013; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Antelopes; Gardens; Children; Group Portraits; Women; Arabic Writing; Men; Animals; Fezes/Tarbouches; Outdoors; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Two men playing cards and smoking. 8.4 x 10.8 cm, Undated; cuid580; 1014; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Card Games; Clocks/Watches; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A small family group, two people sit in a conversation chair. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, Undated; cuid581; 1015; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Girls; Facial Hair; Women; Men; Furnishings; Group Portraits; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A school group with three men. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, 1 February 1935; cuid582; 1016; Photo Shoukry, Mansoura (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Children; Mansoura, Egypt; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Teachers; Schools/Education; Boys; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Students; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A young woman in a dress with shoulder detailing. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 13 May 1949; cuid583; 1017; Studio Racine - Alexandrie, 13 Rue Stamboul (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Individual Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Furnishings; Clocks/Watches
  - A multi-generational family group. 8.7 x 13.5 cm, 28 July 1944; cuid584; 1018; Studio - Nuri Hamza Rustem, Fotografhanesi, Emirler Carsisi, Izmir (Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Men; Izmir, Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits
  - A baby girl with a doll. 8.6 x 13.6 cm, Undated; cuid585; 1019; K. Jacob, Egypt (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Toys; Arabic Writing; Girls; Egypt; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs
  - Three men in suits resting on a car in front of a restaurant. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, 16 May 1937; cuid586; 1020; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Cars/Trucks; Group Portraits; Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Restaurants/bars; Transportation
  - A boat off of Rhoda Island, Cairo, Egypt. 9.1 x 12.1 cm, March 1944; cuid587; 1021; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Arabic Writing; Nile River; Boats/Ships; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A family group of men in a garden (same family from ref617 and 618). 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid588; 1022; Studio - Georges Sargologo, Sirkedji 12, Constantinople (Sirkeci, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Boys; Men; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gardens; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Smoking; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A couple and a young man seated in the grass (same family from ref616 and ref618). 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid589; 1023; Studio - Georges Sargologo, Sirkedji 12, Constantinople (Sirkeci, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Gardens; Boys; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A multi-generational group in a park (same family as ref616 and ref617). 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid590; 1024; Studio - Georges Sargologo, Sirkedji 12, Constantinople (Sirkeci, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Gardens; Head Covers/Veils; Children; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Constantinople; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A man in double-breasted suit looking off camera. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid591; 1025; Studio Shahen, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Men; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - Two women wearing detailed dresses and handbags. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid592; 1026; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Bags/Purses; Egypt; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils
  - A Fallahi, holding an umbrella. 11.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid593; 1027; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Umbrellas/Parasols; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A baby on a swing. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid594; 1028; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Parks; Children; Egypt; Individual Portraits
  - Three men stand around a table, one holds a pen to paper. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid595; 1029; Studio Photo Rico, 2 Rue Istamboul - Alexandrie, Immeuble de la Communauté Israélite (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Group Portraits; Signatures; Pens/Inkwells; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Facial Hair
  - A group sit at a table next to a beach. 8.5 x 13.6 cm, 1967; cuid596; 1030; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Head Covers/Veils; Armenian Writing; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Photographic Prints; Signatures; Gelatin Silver Prints; Abu Qir, Egypt; Women; Men; Cigarettes; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - Two women, one in fur coat, and a man wearing a bow tie. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid597; 1031; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fur Garments; Women; Group Portraits; Men; Bow Ties; Egypt
  - A woman in a black dress leaning on chair. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid598; 1032; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pianos; Books; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Women; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Furnishings
  - A bride with large flower bouquet with a floor length veil. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid599; 1033; Studio S. Zoulis, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Gloves; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Weddings; Individual Portraits; Women; Studio Photography; Weddings
  - A group gathered around a table covered with bread rolls. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid600; 1034; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Parties; Houses; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Food; Men; Group Portraits; Drinks/Beverages; Food; Furnishings; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Two young men in matching jackets and white clothes. Dores, Alexandria, Egypt. 13.0 x 8.1 cm, Undated; cuid601; 1035; Studio - Dores, Alexandrie (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Children; Studio Photography; Boys; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - A man with a mustache wearing a collared shirt. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 17 December 1956; cuid602; 1036; Studio Costa & Abbas, Alexandria (Al Attarin, Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A child seated on an animal headed bench. 13.7 x 8.8 cm, 17 October 1936; cuid603; 1037; Studio Photo London, M. Galoyan, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Children; Furnishings; Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - Two Greek men in suits, smoking cigarettes in a park. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, 21 May 1933; cuid604; 1038; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Signatures; Egypt; Greek Writing; Parks; Smoking; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group wedding portrait. 8.7 x 13.1 cm, Undated; cuid605; 1039; Photo Stelios Rittas, Rue Du Patriarcat Grec - Alex, Nouvel Immeuble 1er. Etage. No. 15 (Alexandria, Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Photographic Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Alexandria, Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Weddings; Men; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Group Portraits
  - A view of a restaurant with staff. 9.0 x 14.3 cm, Undated; cuid606; 1040; Kofler, Theodor (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Cairo, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Waiters; Furnishings; Restaurants/bars; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - Chefs and kitchen staff and waiters. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid607; 1041; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Waiters; Photographic Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Uniforms; Men; Restaurants/bars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Chefs; Facial Hair
  - Four children pose with various props against a painted backdrop. 8.6 x 13.6 cm, Undated; cuid608; 1042; Studio M. Khaled (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Books; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Girls; Boys
  - Two men in military uniform. 12.0 x 8.8 cm, 29 July 1938; cuid609; 1043; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Greek Writing; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits
  - A seated woman with two girls wearing black bows in their hair 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid610; 1044; Studio Photo Moderne, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Armenian Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Bags/Purses; Painted Backdrops; Women; Girls; Alexandria, Egypt; Studio Photography; Children; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - Two men in suits and a woman in a bathing suit pose on a boat. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, 3 July 1931; cuid611; 1045; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Boats/Ships; Cesme, Izmir, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Beaches; Women; Seas; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Turkish Writing; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Men; Transportation; Coast
  - Two seated women with a standing man in a sailor's uniform. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid612; 1046; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Men; Navy; Women; Group Portraits
  - Two men in suits. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid613; 1047; Studio Foto Sedat Izmir, Hukumet Caddesi (Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Men; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Group Portraits
  - Two women seated on a bench. 13.9 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid614; 1048; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Clocks/Watches; Furnishings; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits
  - A group of three men and two women swimming in a pool. 9.4 x 14.3 cm, Undated; cuid615; 1049; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women; Men; Swimming; Swimming Pools; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A woman seated in a wicker chair outdoors in front of a stone building. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid616; 1050; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Furnishings; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A negative image of four women sitting at a cafe. 9.1 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid617; 1051; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Fur Garments; Drinks/Beverages; Restaurants/bars; Women; Negative Images; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt
  - A woman wearing a dark outfit with a white collar and white gloves. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid618; 1052; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Gloves; Bags/Purses; Studio Photography; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Furnishings
  - A multi-generational group pose in front of a building. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid619; 1053; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Photographic Prints; Buildings; Fezes/Tarbouches; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Clocks/Watches; Children; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A couple standing in doorway, a man wearing a tarbouche and glasses holds a woman's face, possibly from a film. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid620; 1054; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Photographic Prints; Films; Women; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits
  - A hand-painted portrait of a woman wearing a blue jacket. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid621; 1055; Studio Photo London, 26 Boulevard Abbas, Heliopolis (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Women; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Jewelry
  - A woman wearing an outfit with a lace collar, looking off camera. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid622; 1056; Studio Photo Oases, Heliopolis (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Women; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A young man in a suit with a book on his lap. M. Sheredan. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid623; 1057; Jenkins, C.; Heyworth's Studios, St. Annes on Sea, England (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Lancashire, England, UK; English Writing; England, UK; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Books; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings
  - A studio portrait of a couple, the woman wears a dress with a patterned collar. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid624; 1058; Studio Badr (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Women; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Egypt; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Furnishings
  - Women and children gathered around a fountain, filling a jug with water. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid625; 1059; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Fountains; Children; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A group sitting in a boat (linked ref655). 8.7 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid626; 1060; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Egypt; Women; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Nile River; Girls; Group Portraits
  - Two women from ref654 standing on the stairs of a porch in front of a house. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid627; 1061; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits
  - Traditional folk dancing, by a group of young women and men. 9.1 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid674; 1108; Studio Photo M. Deroumia, Bab Idriss, Lebanon (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Regional/National Dress; Men; Dancing; Costumes; Beirut, Lebanon; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Europeans in the countryside with a dog sitting in front. "Ingrid" written on the reverse. 8.5 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid675; 1109; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Animals; Buildings; Unknown Locations; Houses; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Dogs; Countryside/Rural; Boys; Girls; Children
  - A soldier in uniform, with a cigarette and gloves in his hands. Victoria Portrait. 12.5 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid676; 1110; Victoria Portrait (Bernhard Wachtl, Wien) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cigarettes; Gloves; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Swords/Knives; Egypt; Uniforms; Vienna, Austria; Men; Weapons; Books; Furnishings
  - A group of men and women all wearing a similar hats in a garden/park. English text on reverse talks of "childhood friends". Same writing as ref706. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, 21 May 1895; cuid677; 1111; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Berlin, Germany; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; English Writing; Hats; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Men; Facial Hair
  - Soldiers in military uniform posing with a sign that reads "Libesgaben werden entgegengenomen". Same handwriting as ref705. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, 21 May 1895; cuid678; 1112; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Postcards; German Writing; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Cigarettes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers; Berlin, Germany; Group Portraits; Men; Signatures; Facial Hair
  - Two men in suits standing outdoors. French text on reverse: "Souvenir of an excursion to the dams with the University". Same man from ref708. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, 18 March 1938; cuid679; 1113; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Students; Signatures; Men; Egypt; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Group Portraits; Universities; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Three young men in suits in a garden. French text on reverse: "Souvenir of Thursday, 1 March 1934, passed pleasantly in the garden." Same man from ref706. 8.9 x 14.2 cm, cuid680; 1114; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Parks; Group Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Gardens; French Writing
  - A couple feeding the pigeons at the Piazza Sr. Marco in Venice. Names written on reverse. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, 1941; cuid681; 1115; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Birds; Venice, Italy; Animals; Architecture; Women; Men; Italian Writing; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A woman leaning on a column in a black dress with a fan. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid682; 1116; Studio - Imperial Photo Studio, Kamel Street, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Women; Hand Fans; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings
  - Two men shaking hands in front of a painted backdrop with columns. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid683; 1117; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Men; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - Two men standing on the steps of a building, one is holding a cigarette. 13.7 x8.6 cm, Undated; cuid684; 1118; A.S. Milionis, Alexandria (Egypt) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Cigarettes; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Uniforms; Alexandria, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - An elderly woman looking off camera wearing a dark coat. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid685; 1119; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Women; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A young woman in a white dress with a large white bow in her hair and man in a short suit. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid686; 1120; Studio Nicolas Pappazoglou, Le Caire, Egypte (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Clocks/Watches; Girls; Boys; Women; Group Portraits; Children; Furnishings; Bags/Purses; Gloves; Clocks/Watches
  - A man in a suit looking off camera. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid687; 1121; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Egypt; Facial Hair
  - A man, woman and three children posing for a family portrait. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid688; 1122; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Girls; Women; Men; Medals/Insignia; Religious Crosses; Children; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A cropped portrait of a young man wearing a suit and a tiepin. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid689; 1123; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Egypt; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - Two buses with the same logo in front of some large buildings. 8.1 x 13.0 cm, Undated; cuid690; 1124; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Costumes; Photographic Prints; Buses; Transportation; Arabic Writing
  - A young man in a Christian religious outfit holding a book with a cross on it. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid691; 1125; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Religious Crosses; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Children
  - A multi-generational group in a studio portrait. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid692; 1126; Studio - Hanein (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Girls; Bow Ties; Egypt; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Children
  - A baby with a religious pendent on a pillow (same handwriting as ref722). 13.7 x 8.7 cm, 21 September 1917; cuid693; 1127; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Arabic Writing; Children; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Furnishings
  - A baby lying on its stomach on a fur blanket (same handwriting as ref721). 8.5 x 13.5 cm, 1927; cuid694; 1128; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Jewelry; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Children; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Furnishings
  - Seven men wearing tarbouches. 8.3 x 1.5 cm, Undated; cuid695; 1129; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Canes/Walking Sticks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A man with his arm around a boy at the beach. 8.7 x 13.5 cm, Undated; cuid765; 1198; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Beaches; Seas; Boys; Men; Egypt; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A man wearing a boater hat on horseback. (same building as ref815). 14.4 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid773; 1206; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Individual Portraits; Hats; Photographic Prints; Horses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Animals; Buildings
  - Construction workers. 9.7 x 9.7 cm, Undated; cuid774; 1207; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 14)